Centre for Canadian Studies fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Centre for Canadian Studies fonds
1969 - 1988
F-64
1 m of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Centre for Canadian Studies
The Canadian Studies program developed from a series of informal meetings among a group of interested faculty members in late 1969 and early 1970. Subsequently representatives from eight departments and the library drafted a proposal for a Canadian Studies program within the Division of General Studies (later the Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies). Course offerings began in the fall of 1971. The program was intended to provide a corrective for the lack of Canadian content being offered in the University and to provide a focus for interdisciplinary study.
By 1978, the University had appointed a full-time director for the program. The director was advised by a Steering Committee with one member from each department in the University which offered courses acceptable for credit towards the minor in Canadian Studies. The Steering Committee also included representatives from the Faculty of Education, the library, and the Student Society.
In 1980, the program was redesignated as the Centre for Canadian Studies, and offered students a major and honours in Canadian Studies. In addition, the Centre developed a French Canadian Studies Certificate Program.
Upon the dissolution of the Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies in 1985, the Centre for Canadian Studies became part of the Division of Interdisciplinary Studies within the Faculty of Arts.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the provenance.
Fonds consists of records created or received by the Centre for Canadian Studies in the course of administering its program and carrying out its operational functions. Activities and topics documented include the establishment, organization, and operation of the Centre, and the development and delivery of courses to undergraduate students. Fonds includes Canadian Studies Steering Committee agendas, minutes, and related papers; correspondence; reports; course proposals and descriptions; and other documents.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Lorimer, Rowland M.; Copes, Parzival; Nesbitt, Bruce; Koroscil, P.M.
The records were transferred to Archives through the regular application of university Records Retention Schedules and Disposal Authorities (RRSDAs).
All accessions have been processed as of May 2004. Further accruals are expected.
For other material relating to the Centre for Canadian Studies, see the inventory for the Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies fonds, F-23. Also consult the finding aid for the Institute of Fisheries Analysis fonds, F-240.
Access to some files may be restricted in accordance with the provisions of British Columbia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (RSBC 1996 c. 165). Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Administration and organization, 1969 - 1985; F-64-1; 23 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the development, administration, organization and operation of the Canadian Studies Program and its successor, the Centre for Canadian Studies. Series includes Steering Committee agendas, minutes and papers; reports; proposals; and other documents.
  The arrangement was provided by the archivist.
  Further accruals to the series are expected.
  Access to files containing personal information may be restricted in accordance with the provisions of British Columbia's Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act (RSBC 1996 c. 165). Files marked "pending review" must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review some files may be restricted in accordance with the FOI/POP Act. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
  A file list is available.
  - State of Canadian Studies at SFU, 1969; F-64-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - Proposal for establishment of Canadian Studies program, 1970; F-64-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies program - Library collection, 1971; F-64-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1969 - 1972; F-64-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1970 - 1971; F-64-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1972 - 1973; F-64-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1971 - 1973; F-64-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1971 - 1976; F-64-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1972 - 1980; F-64-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1974 - 1978; F-64-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1977 - 1982; F-64-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 64-1)
  - Canadian Studies Policy Committee, 1972; F-64-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Canadian Studies annual report, 1972; F-64-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Report to Commission on Canadian Studies, 1972 - 1973; F-64-1-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Canadian Studies semester reports, 1973; F-64-1-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Proposal for the establishement - submission to Senate, November 1970; F-64-1-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Questionnaire - Canadian Studies, 1974 - 1976; F-64-1-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - University Review committee - Canadian Studies program, December 1977; F-64-1-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Director - search, 1977 - 1978; F-64-1-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Secretary to Director - job description, 1979 - 1982; F-64-1-0-0-21 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Faculty Orgranization Task Force, 1980; F-64-1-0-0-22 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Canadian Studies questionnaire, 1982; F-64-1-0-0-23 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Profile - Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies, 1983; F-64-1-0-0-24 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Canadian Studies transfer to Faculty of Arts, 1984 - 1985; F-64-1-0-0-25 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
- Correspondence, 1970 - 1985; F-64-2; 8 cm of textual records
  Series consists primarily of correspondence created or received by the Director of the Canadian Studies Program but includes some reports and other types of documents. Includes one file of correspondence about the Canadian Studies Program that had been originally received by the Office of the Dean, Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies.
  - Director's correspondence, 1970 - 1972; F-64-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Director's correspondence, 1971 - 1973; F-64-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Correspondence from Faculty of Arts, 1975 - 1979; F-64-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-2)
  - Chair's correspondence with regional colleges, 1979 - 1984; F-64-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - Wise, Sidney, 1979; F-64-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - Associate Director, 1980 - 1983; F-64-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - President - correspondence, 1980 - 1984; F-64-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - Munro, Patrick - CBC, Three's Company, 1980; F-64-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - Page, Jim, 1980; F-64-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - Faculty of Interdisciplinary Studies, 1981 - 1984; F-64-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - Correspondence - Director's, 1985; F-64-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
- Curriculum and instruction files, 1970 - 1988; F-64-3; 44 cm of textual records; General note: The archivist discarded files F-64-3-0-0-1, and F-64-3-0-0-2 because they were duplicated by documents contained in the accrual.
  Series consists of records relating to the development and delivery of courses that constituted the Canadian Studies program including courses for the certificate in French Canadian Studies and a proposed French bilingual program. Records include correspondence, proposals, reports, course outlines, and other documents.
  - Curriculum and instruction - general files, 1978 - 1985; F-64-3-1; 3 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to curriculum and instruction generally, not falling under a more specific category. Activites and events documented include the provision of Canadian content courses by other departments, grading policies, and scheduling. Records include course outlines, corresopndence, policies, and schedules.
    Further accruals to the sub-series are expected.
    - Canadian content courses - other departments, 1978; F-64-3-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - English 221 - prerequisites, 1979; F-64-3-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Grading guidelines and standards - CN.S., 1979 - 1984; F-64-3-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Schedule of CN.S. courses, 1980 - 1985; F-64-3-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
  - Program and course proposals, 1973 - 1983; F-64-3-2; 12 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the development of individual courses in Canadian Studies as well as the requirements for a minor and major in Canadian Studies and the provision for a joint major with other departments. Records include correspondence, proposals, and surveys.
    - Canadian Studies - course proposals and papers, 1973 - 1974; F-64-3-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Prior versions of Canadian Studies curriculum proposal, [197-?]; F-64-3-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Major program - letter of intent to Universities Council of B.C., 1977; F-64-3-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Major program - student survey (demand) including preference re: French requirement, 1977; F-64-3-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Old Major proposal, vol. 1, 1977 - 1978; F-64-3-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Old Major proposal, vol. 2, 1977 - 1978; F-64-3-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 64-3)
    - Proposal for Major in Canadian Studies, 1977 - 1978; F-64-3-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Board of Governors' Action on Canadian Studies curriculum proposal, 1979; F-64-3-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Canadian Studies proposals (3) as approved by FISC (SCUS 79-60), 1979; F-64-3-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Canadian Studies new program proposal (Paper S.80-4), 1979; F-64-3-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Curriculum committees - Faculties CN.S. request for approval, 1979; F-64-3-2-0-11 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Joint Major - approvals from departments, 1979; F-64-3-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Curriculum - letters of support, 1979; F-64-3-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Major in Canadian Studies proposal, 1980; F-64-3-2-0-14 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Registrar - correspondence re: CN.S. curriculum propoals, 1979; F-64-3-2-0-15 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - SCAP - Canadian Studies' submissions, 1979 - 1980; F-64-3-2-0-16 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Universities' Council action on new curriculum proposals, 1980; F-64-3-2-0-17 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Universities' Council - CN.S. proposal and Birch's transmittal memo, 1980; F-64-3-2-0-18 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - BC Studies certificate program, 1980 - 1983; F-64-3-2-0-19 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Minor program - transition to new program, 1981; F-64-3-2-0-20 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - Estonian Studies, 1982 - 1983; F-64-3-2-0-21 (Archival box - small 64-9)
      Restricted in part
    - Estonian Studies - proposals and funding details, 1982 - 1983; F-64-3-2-0-22 (Archival box - small 64-9)
      Open
    - Estonian Studies - Endowed Chairs, 1983; F-64-3-2-0-23 (Archival box - small 64-9)
    - Centre for Canadian Studies course proposals, 1985; F-64-3-2-0-24 (Archival box - small 64-9)
  - Course files, 1971 - 1986; F-64-3-3; 17 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records documenting the content and evaluation standards of courses. Records include course outlines and descriptions; reading lists; and assignments and essay questions.
    - Course offereings, 1972 - 1983; F-64-3-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 001-3, 1974 - 1978; F-64-3-3-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 100-3, 1973; F-64-3-3-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 111-3, 1973; F-64-3-3-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 121-3 Mosaic or Melting Pot, 1974; F-64-3-3-0-5 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 160-3, 1981 - 1986; F-64-3-3-0-6 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 200-3, 1971 - 1978; F-64-3-3-0-7 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 200/201/202-3, 1976 - 1978; F-64-3-3-0-8 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 200/201/202-3, 1978 - 1979; F-64-3-3-0-9 (Archival box - standard 64-4)
    - CN.S 200/201/202-3, 1980; F-64-3-3-0-10 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 210-3, 1981 - 1986; F-64-3-3-0-11 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 280-3, 1980 - 1986; F-64-3-3-0-12 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 350-3, 1981 - 1985; F-64-3-3-0-13 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 390/391-3, 1980 - 1981; F-64-3-3-0-14 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 390/391-4, 1982; F-64-3-3-0-15 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 390/391-5, 1983 - 1986; F-64-3-3-0-16 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 400/401-5, 1972 - 1977; F-64-3-3-0-17 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 400/401-6, 1978 - 1980; F-64-3-3-0-18 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 400/401-7, 1980; F-64-3-3-0-19 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
    - CN.S 490/491-3, 1981 - 1986; F-64-3-3-0-20 (Archival box - standard 64-5)
  - French language program files, 1977 - 1988; F-64-3-4; 12 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records documenting the discussion of a mandatory French language requirement for Canadian Studies majors, a proposal for a Canadian Studies program in French, and the development and delivery of a French-Canadian studies certificate program. Records include correspondence, proposals, brochures, questionnaires, and other documents.
    - French requirement—students with French language training, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Data on French language competence, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French language requirement completed ballots, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French language requirement master ballot, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French language requirement tabulated results, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-5 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French language requirement review in 3 years, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-6 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French language requirement justification for lack, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French language requirement Merler/Lincoln memos, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French Western Canada studies program, 1977; F-64-3-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Bilingual program comments, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Joint major French Canadian studies, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-11 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Bilingual program teaching in French survey DLLL, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-12 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Bilingual program teaching in French survey depts., 1979; F-64-3-4-0-13 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Canadian Studies instruction in French proposal ad hoc ctte., 1979; F-64-3-4-0-14 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French Canadian studies comments, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-15 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French medium instruction inventory of instruction capabilities, 1979; F-64-3-4-0-16 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Bilingual program proposal, 1980; F-64-3-4-0-17 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Bilingual program letters of support, 1980; F-64-3-4-0-18 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French Canadian studies proposal, 1980; F-64-3-4-0-19 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Bilingual program staffing of French courses, 1983; F-64-3-4-0-20 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Program of studies in French proposal, 1985; F-64-3-4-0-21 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Studies in French at SFU proposal, 1985; F-64-3-4-0-22 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Studies in French background material, 1985 - 1986; F-64-3-4-0-23 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Studies in French program proposal, 1985 - 1986; F-64-3-4-0-24 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Survey of French majors, 1987; F-64-3-4-0-25 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Teaching in French dept. replies, 1987; F-64-3-4-0-26 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - French education Faculty of Education, 1988; F-64-3-4-0-27 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
    - Continuing Studies French Canadian certificate brochure, 1980 - 1983; F-64-3-4-0-28 (Archival box - standard 64-6)
- Committee files, 1978 - 1985; F-64-4; 8 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the meetings and deliberations of the Centre's committees, and university committees in which the Centre participated. Records include meeting agendas, minutes and supporting papers.
  - Canadian Studies Steering Committee files, 1978 - 1985; F-64-4-1; 2 cm of textual records
    - Canadian Studies Steering Committee, 1984 - 1985; F-64-4-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
    - Steering committee membership, 1978 - 1984; F-64-4-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
  - Canadian Studies Curriculum Committee files, 1979 - 1983; F-64-4-2; 1 cm of textual records
    - Curriculum Committee, 1979 - 1983; F-64-4-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
  - Canadian Studies Graduate Develoment Committee files, 1982 - 1984; F-64-4-3; 1 cm of textual records
    - Canadian Studies Graduate Develoment Committee, 1982 - 1984; F-64-4-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
  - President's Advisory Committee on University Priorities files, 1983 - 1985; F-64-4-4; 2 cm of textual records
    - PACUP--Canadian Studies Review, 1983 - 1985; F-64-4-4-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
    - PACUP, 1984; F-64-4-4-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
  - Senate Committee on Academic Planning files, 1984; F-64-4-5; 1 cm of textual records
    Senate Committee on University Priorities
    - Senate Committee on Academic Planning, 1984; F-64-4-5-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
  - Undergraduate Curriculum Task Force files, 1985; F-64-4-6; 1 cm of textual records
    Undergraduate Curriculum Task Force
    - Undergraduate Curriculum Task Force, 1985; F-64-4-6-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
- Subject files, 1976 - 1985; F-64-5; 3 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to topics of interest to the Centre for Canadian Studies. Records include correspondence, reports, and other documents.
  - Symons Report—Implications for graduate studies at SFU, 1976 - 1981; F-64-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
  - Canadian studies role in Canadian universities, 1981; F-64-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
  - Canadian studies careers, 1984 - 1985; F-64-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
- Student relations, 1981; F-64-6; 1 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to students of the Centre for Canadian studies. Activities, events and topics documented include student representation on the Canadian Studies Steering Committee. Records include correspondence.
  - Student representation in Canadian Studies, 1981; F-64-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-7)
- Special events, 1973 - 1985; F-64-7; 6 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to conferences, seminars, and other special events in which the Centre participated. Records include correspondence, reports, proposals, lists and other documents.
  - Report of the Canadian Studies Conference at SFU, 1973; F-64-7-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
  - Canadian Studies seminars, 1978 - 1983; F-64-7-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
  - Conference proposal—achievements of F.R. Scott, 1980 - 1981; F-64-7-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
  - Monique Jutras visit, 1985; F-64-7-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
- Publications and posters, 1970 - 1985; F-64-8; 7 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to publicizing the course offerings of the Centre for Canadian Studies. Records include posters, newsletters, brochures and other documents.
  - Publications, 1970 - 1985; F-64-8-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
    Previous reference code assigned by SFU Archives: F-64-1-0-16.
  - Posters—course offerings, 1973 - 1985; F-64-8-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
  - Student notes newsletter, 1979 - 1981; F-64-8-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
  - Publicity, 1979 - 1985; F-64-8-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 64-8)
  - Canadian studies booklet, 1983; F-64-8-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 64-8)